josef heidegger

Wiener Straße 60-62/2/12, 3400 Klosterneuburg, Austria

Accomplished team lead with more than 9 years of industry experience in product and project/agency environments.

I am acquainted with people management, mentoring, hiring, technical interviews and have a strong team spirit. With my solid technical background, experience with product development and my proficiency in agile methodologies, delivery processes and development practices, I bring a broad skillset for setting up strategies and improving processes. As an open minded and approachable personality with strong values and ethics I strive to shape my team's culture.

experience

2016-08-2020-03 (3.7Y)

Lead Developer & Scrum Master WorkHeld/Tablet Solutions GmbH

Lead of the development team (4ppl) of a SaaS startup in the field of process digitalization in industrial construction.

In my role as technical lead I took a big part in lifting the product from an early MVP into a robust, highly customizable SaaS platform that it is now.

Having a strong interest in process and development frameworks, I played a big part in shaping the agile mindset of the company. By becoming Scrum Master, I helped my team with guidance and by continuously questioning and improving our processes.

Responsible for the engineering department, I recruited most of the development and QA team and nurtured the team's motivation and growth. I set up technical standards and guidelines, established a DevOps mindset and added BDD, test automation and production monitoring into our development process; enabling fast value delivery to the user, and ensuring that we are building a robust product.

I was also working closely with the PO on defining user stories and test scenarios, backlog prioritization and long-term feature planning.

2011-01-2016-07

Software Developer EMAKINA CEE (formerly diamond:dogs GmbH)

2016-07 (5.5Y)

IC for various projects for Austrian and international customers.

I had the opportunity to work with some great minds and get a fundamental understanding of state-of-the-art software development practices and an indepth understanding of the .NET framework and web technologies.

education

2006–2009 Software Engineering

University of Applied Sciences Upper Austria, Campus Hagenberg

1997-2005 BG/BRG Gmunden

languages

German Native (C2)
English Proficient (C1)
French Basic (A1)

certifications

2018 Certified Scrum Master (Mitch Lacey/Scrum Alliance)

personal

I am passionate about innovations and technology, always keen on learning new methodologies and frameworks. In my spare time I like to find peace in nature and photography, get lessons from history, get myself excited about team-sports and try to find new personal challenges with downhill mountain biking. As a positive person who is striving for happiness, I won't miss a chance for a good laugh:)

contact

- m josef.heidegger@outlook.at
- **p** +43 699 1967 58 68
- w https://sendit.space/josef-heidegger

skills

People and Leadership

- Coaching, mentoring & sponsorship
- Hiring & technical interviews
- Approachable and helpful
- Good listener and calm personality
- Empathic
- Self-reflected
- Sense of humor
- Team player
- Strong sense of ownership
- Situational Leadership
- Sharp mind and excellent problem-solving skills
- Good at seeing the big picture

Product and Project

- Scrum
- Agile Project Management
- SaaS Product Development
- Domain Driven Design
- Behaviour Driven Development
- Test Driven Development
- Requirements Engineering
- Release Planning
- Documentation
- Code reviews
- Story Pattern
- Testing Pyramid
- Test Automation/Gherkin
- GitFlov
- Trunk Based Development
- Continuous Delivery
- Jira/Confluence
- GitHub

Development and DevOps

- CI/CD
- OOP
- Design Patterns
- Unit and Integration Testing
- Reactive Programming
- Git
- C#/.NET
- ASP.NET Core, EF Core
- TypeScript, JavaScript
 - HTML/CSS
- Angular
- Xamarin (Android, iOS, UWP)
- SQL (MSSQL/SQLite)
 - NoSQL
- Redis
- API Design
- Cloud Computing (Azure, AWS)
- Micro Services
- Docker
- Azure DevOps
- TeamCity
- ELK/Elasticsearch